[Lloyd] I've been so focused
on finding it,
I'm only realizing now,
I have no idea
what's waiting for me
in that temple.
The Arc Dragon was very...
nonspecific.
Well, the Temple
of the Dragon Cores
was run by a helpful
spirit guardian.
Maybe it'll be like that?
All I know is,
there'll be some "ritual"
to help me reach
my true potential
as the Green Ninja.
The Dragon also said
the ritual was something
you would not survive.
Yeah, trying not to think
about that part.
How do we open it?
[disembodied whispering]
[vines rustling]
Unh!
Lloyd, you're sealed off!
It's a trap!
Oh!
Uh, or... not?
[sighing]
Guess I'm doing this one alone.
Or-- hear me out--
you could just not do it?
This doesn't have to be
your responsibility, Lloyd.
But it does, Arin.
I'm the Green Ninja,
but I've never discovered
that true potential.
Plus, this is
the only chance we have
to fix the messed up state
of Elemental Energy
in our world,
so... I have to take the risk.
I knew you were gonna say
something like that.
Good luck, old friend.
See you on the other side.
Hello?
Anyone?
I'm outside now?
Hey!
[straining]
Ah!
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Jump up, kick back
whip around and spin ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ Whip around and spin ♪
♪ For what's right ♪♪
[Rontu]
Thank you for your care,
but like Egalt before me,
my time is near.
No, Master Rontu,
don't say that.
Together we'll fight
for your recovery.
I've sent Jenny and Barry
for supplies.
I'll cook you
the most restorative bowl of--
There is no point.
Riyu,
my final student,
also lays dying,
somewhere in a distant land.
What? No...
I'm sure that's not true.
I can feel it.
He's fading,
passing from this life,
as I am.
Your suffering
must be causing bad dreams.
It's no dream,
but it is my fault.
If I had been
a better teacher,
I should not have let him go.
I didn't protect him,
and now he...
will...
die.
[groaning sadly]
[wheezing breath]
[groaning]
Don't worry, Riyu.
Sora and Frak
will get you what you need.
You'll be fine.
Where are they?
Why aren't they back yet?
-[Frak] Come on!
-[both panting]
[Frak] We gotta
catch that monster
before it destroys
everything onboard!
[Sora] I'm more worried
about getting its energy
to save Riyu.
[panting]
[Frak] What direction
do you think
that scream come from?
[Sora] Not sure.
We'd better split up.
We don't have much time.
H'up!
H'ah!
-[yelping]
-Shh!
[Sora whispering] I thought
you were the monster.
I saw it.
I've been trying to hide.
[Sora] You're the one
who screamed?
Which direction did it go?
[distant high squealing]
[squeal reverberating]
[Sora panting]
[squealing echoing]
[air squealing
through rattling slats]
[sound stops abruptly]
[Sora sighing in relief]
[Frak whispering]
Someone there?
Who are you?
What are you doing on this ship?
Did you free
that elemental monster?
Ugh!
Get back here!
[Frak panting]
[Sora screaming nearby]
[Frak] Sora!
-[Sora gasping]
-[monster hissing]
[Sora] Ah! No!
H'ah!
[snarling]
Ah!
Nope.
I need that!
[monster snarling]
[Frak] Sora!
We can't let it escape!
It's Riyu's only hope!
[snarling]
No!
[Reggie] What?
My creature escaped?
What kind of Ninja are you?
That monster
is my valuable property!
[both] H'yah!
That's right, go get it back,
or you'll have
the Explorer's Club of Ninjago
to answer to!
[groaning]
Ah!
[boy giggling deviously]
[mischievous laughing]
Hello?
A-Are you...
the Spirit of this Temple?
[♪♪♪]
I've seen some weird
Source Dragon visions,
but seriously, what was that?
[boy] Why ask me, old man?
No way...
Yes way.
I'm the seed that grew into you,
and you're the seed
that will grow
into your future self.
Well, that is,
unless your life ends here.
[giggling deviously]
[Cole] Ras came through
the Monastery,
fighting everyone in his path,
for the library?
[Geo] This isn't the Cyrus Borg
Children's Reading Room,
it's Master Wu's study.
It's gotta have secrets
Ras would want, right?
[Cole] I guess.
To be honest,
I'm not sure
what Wu kept in here.
Mr. Frohicky
is not going to like this.
He's got bigger problems
right now.
Rontu isn't looking so good.
Can't believe
I got so hotheaded
I ran right into that fight
with Nokt.
I could've been here,
I could have
protected everyone from Ras.
Or... you'd be trapped
wherever
all the other Ninja are.
It can't be a coincidence
Ras used the Gates,
then they stopped working
right after that.
These scrolls...
They're all about finding,
and containing, energy,
and they're numbered,
but one is missing,
and one guess who took it.
Didn't Ras capture
a Source Dragon?
Sounds like he's pretty good
at containing energy already.
Unless it's something specific
he needs to contain.
Something specific
to Master Wu's knowledge.
[Frak and Sora panting]
[Frak] You'd think
an Elemental Monster
would be easier to track down.
[distant screaming]
[Sora] I'm guessing that way.
[villagers whimpering in panic]
[monster snarling]
[screaming]
[structure crumbling]
[snarling]
[♪♪♪]
[Sora] Tourists,
am I right?
[monster snarling]
Ah!
[Sora gasping]
[impacts thudding]
Can't they keep it down
out there?
We got a hurt dragon in here!
[Sora] Frak, keep it still!
[Frak]
How am I supposed to do that
when it's trying to blast me
to the Spectral Lands?
[Riyu groaning]
This can't be good.
[monster snarling]
[villagers screaming]
Ugh!
They had one job!
[monster snarling]
Are you two completely
incompetent without me?
It's like watching Lava Tides
trying to square dance!
Now's not the time for jokes!
Who's joking?
Get that energy to Riyu,
I can hold this thing back.
Yeah, we, uh,
didn't get the energy yet.
What?
Are you two trying
to break the record
for Most Failed Mission?
[roaring]
Ugh!
Okay,
I'll turn up the heat,
you get to work.
H'ah!
[powers fritzing]
Ah!
Ugh!
I keep forgetting
about our messed up powers!
Annoying!
We've gotta do this
the old-fashioned way.
What does that mean?
Take black and white pictures?
No. Classic Ninja moves,
without Elemental Powers.
H'yah!
Ah!
Hi'yah!
Uh, hope this isn't sacred
or anything.
That flag has stood
in that spot
for five centuries.
Wow!
Someone's living in the past.
Hi'yah!
H'yah!
H'ah! Y'ah!
Hi'yah! Yah! Yah!
I'm... afraid of her.
-Hup!
-H'yah!
[all grunting with effort]
H'yah!
Ah!
Sora! Now!
[device powering up]
Riyu!
No!
[sighing in relief]
Nice catch, Freya!
[monster snarling]
H'yah! H'ah!
Don't worry about us!
Save Riyu!
[Sora] Please be enough...
[Riyu wheezing]
[groaning softly]
[bellowing]
[Wyldfyre] H'yah!
[Frak] Huah!
[Wyldfyre] H'ah!
[panting]
We need to use the environment
to our strategic advantage.
Ugh!
Even in a fight,
you talk all boring!
What I mean is--
force that thing
into the dead end!
It can't escape.
Now, that's an idea.
[monster snarling]
Hah!
H'yah!
H'ah!
[monster hissing]
H'yah!
H'ah!
Hah! H'yah!
[energy surging]
Frak?
It's acting all freaky!
[monster snarling]
[roaring]
We're going to need
a bigger dead end.
Since when can it do that?
[monster roaring]
Are you... really me?
I mean, young me?
[laughing]
Why are you even asking that?
You know it's true.
Are you here to guide me?
[laughing]
Does a tree guide
what happens to its seeds?
What's that supposed to mean?
[blowing]
[rumbling]
[gasping]
[Young Lloyd]
This is the Tree of Life.
[bursting sprouts,
trees rumbling]
I...
I don't understand.
Then get to the root
of the mystery.
What am I supposed to be
looking--
for!
[Young Lloyd laughing]
[sniffing] Ooh!
Is that Merlopian seaweed cake
I smell?
Mm! I haven't had that
since our honeymoon,
and it's right here
in our old neighborhood?
Guess everything's
right here now.
We've missed so much, Barry.
When Arin gets back,
he has to give us
a tour of this place.
If he gets back.
I'm worried.
Being a Ninja mom is not easy.
We should start
a Ninja Parent support group.
Great idea,
but first
we gotta get everything
Mr. Frohicky needs--
[woman] What is that?
[man, nervously]
That's normal, right?
[energy crackling]
[snarling]
Maybe this is just
a regular part
of the Crossroads?
[roaring]
[yelping]
[people screaming]
I'm thinking no.
[panicked screaming]
[monster hissing]
[roaring]
Come on, get to safety!
[monster snarling]
[roaring]
Ah!
Hey, you Gormless fopdoodle!
Prepare to face the fury
of the Lariat Launcher!
[blasting]
Ugh!
[groaning]
[Frak] Thanks for
the distraction, Gweeg!
My dad is so wrong about you!
Come on, Riyu.
This can't be it.
[Egalt] Your journey
is not what you think,
young Riyu.
[groaning]
Oh, her heartbeat
is getting weaker.
[Egalt] Rest easy, Morro.
I will handle this one.
Egalt, my love!
I finally rejoin you,
but my passing is not
in the glory of battle
nor the joy of peace.
It is in failure.
Source Dragons have abandoned
the Merged Lands.
All is falling to pieces.
I miss you, dear one,
but this is not your time.
I...
I don't understand.
For good or ill,
your student is important.
Only you can show him the way.
The fate of this cycle
depends on it.
But Riyu is dying.
I can feel it.
He is not going to make it.
Never lose hope, Rontu.
[♪♪♪]
[gasping]
[coughing]
Riyu...
[♪♪♪]
[Wyldfyre grunting with effort]
[heavy thudding]
[battle thudding outside]
[energy surging]
[gasping]
[monster snarling]
Uh!
[monster growling]
H'yah!
Oh!
[snarling]
No...
[energy surging]
[Riyu roaring]
[gasping]
[smashing]
[roaring]
That is the coolest thing
I've ever seen.
That... was
a pretty powerful antidote.
I just wanted him to live.
I had no clue this could happen.
[monster snarling]
[snarling]
[Riyu growling]
[♪♪♪]
[bellowing in victory]
[panting]
[Sora] Riyu!
Look at you, boy!
[Riyu grumble-talking]
-[Sora] Oof!
-[Riyu grumbling fondly]
That was amazing!
We owe you our lives!
I mean,
I totally had that thing,
but thanks for the assist.
[villagers celebrating]
[Gweeg] Good show, old boy!
Good show!
[Loyalist] The monster
was unleashed from the airship,
and it behaved
exactly as you predicted.
[Chief Loyalist]
Of course it did,
but did you get
the information we need?
[Loyalist] Yes.
Recorded at the precise moment
of expansion.
Sending now.
[Chief Loyalist]
Most interesting.
Positive news.
We now know the exact location
of the Weapon.
However,
it is splintered,
in two different locations.
but I promise,
we will find--
and reassemble--
the Weapon of Desolation
for you.
[Empress Beatrix]
Then Imperium,
the Ninja,
and the entire Merged Lands
will bow before me
as I regain my rightful power!
All hail the good Empress.